Finding aid to the Phoebe C. Mulford Papers CA.MS.00345
Smith College Archives
Phoebe C. Mulford Papers
1915-1934
Smith College Archives
Mulford, Phoebe C.
CA.MS.00345
1.042 linear feet (3 containers)
Head of Hubbard House. Contains correspondence, clippings, and flyers.
Biographical / Historical
Phoebe C. Mulford was head of Hubbard House between the years of 1916 and 1929. Later, Mulford owned and operated Northampton's Arnold Inn, which offered affordable rooms to graduate students, faculty, and college guests. Her son, William Mulford, attended the preparatory school Exeter, and then graduated from Harvard University as a member of the class of 1928. The extensive correspondence between the two establish the closeness of their relationship. Phoebe C. Mulford passed away December 31, 1966.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of correspondence between Mulford and her son William Mulford, starting from when he was a young boy, through his studies at Harvard University, and immediately after his 1928 graduation. Also in the collection are various newspaper and magazine clippings, flyers, mementos between mother and son, William's high school report card, and sketches of Smith College campus drawn by her son in 1933 and 1934.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Phoebe C. Mulford papers were donated to the Smith College Archives from a number of sources.
Mulford, Phoebe C.
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1917-April 1917 (Box 947, Folder 1)
- Letters to her son William, May 1917-Dec. 1917 (Box 947, Folder 2)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1918-Sept. 1918 (Box 947, Folder 3)
- Letters to her son William, Oct. 1918-Dec. 1918 (Box 947, Folder 4)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1919-May 1919 (Box 947, Folder 5)
- Letters to her son William, Sept. 1919-Dec. 1919 (Box 947, Folder 6)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1920-Dec. 1920 (Box 947, Folder 7)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1921-Dec. 1921 (Box 947, Folder 8)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1922-Dec. 1922 (Box 947, Folder 9)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1923-Dec. 1923 (Box 947, Folder 10)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1924-June 1924 (Box 947, Folder 11)
- Letters to her son William, Sept. 1924-Dec. 1924 (Box 947, Folder 12)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1925-June 1925 (Box 947, Folder 13)
- Letters to her son William, Sept. 1925-Dec. 1925 (Box 947, Folder 14)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1926-June 1926 (Box 948, Folder 1)
- Letters to her son William, Oct. 1926-Dec. 1926 (Box 948, Folder 2)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1927-May 1927 (Box 948, Folder 3)
- Letters to her son William, Sept. 1927-Dec. 1927 (Box 948, Folder 4)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1928-May 1928 (Box 948, Folder 5)
- Letters to her son William, Sept. 1928-Nov. 1928 (Box 948, Folder 6)
- Letters to her son William, Jan. 1929-Nov. 1929 (Box 948, Folder 7)
- Letters from her son William, Sept. 1924-Dec. 1924 (Box 948, Folder 8)
- Letters from her son William, Dec. 1925 (Box 948, Folder 9)
- Letters from her son William, Jan. 1926-June 1926 (Box 948, Folder 10)
- Letters from her son William, Sept. 1927-Dec. 1927 (Box 948, Folder 11)
- Letters from her son William, Jan. 1928-June 1928 (Box 949, Folder 1)
- Letters from her son William, Sept. 1928-Nov. 1928 (Box 949, Folder 2)
- Letters from her son William, Jan. 1929-Aug. 1929 (Box 949, Folder 3)
- Letters from her son William, Oct. 1931-April 1934 (Box 949, Folder 4)
- Sketches of Smith College done by William Mulford, 1933-1934 (Box 949, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous, a. 1916-1928; undated (Box 949, Folder 6)